<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dbcls news - Articles</title>
    <description>Database Center for Life Science (DBCLS) forms a base for integrating databases in life science field. Positioning itself as a specialized institution to provide biological databases and related services, DBCLS integrates and maintains biological databases mainly within Japan, conducts R&amp;D of information technology and develops new services to enhance usability.</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
        
        <item>
          <title>A paper &quot;ChIP-Atlas: a data-mining suite powered by full integration of public ChIP-seq data&quot; was published in EMBO Reports.</title>
          
            <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper “ChIP-Atlas: a data-mining suite powered by full integration of public ChIP-seq data” was published in EMBO Reports. DBCLS’s project researcher Tazro Ohta has been contributing to this project.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ChIP-Atlas &lt;a href=&quot;https://chip-atlas.org&quot;&gt;https://chip-atlas.org&lt;/a&gt; is a database to provide ChIP-Seq/DNase-Seq data retrieved from Sequence Read Archive. The research group retrieved data from the archive and re-analyzed, then developed a web application system that users can view data on genome browser, find target genes and colocalized partners of transcription factors. Users also can submit their lists of genes or regions of genome to perform enrichment analysis using transcription factor binding sites. The paper also showed that the group found the transcription factors regulating tissue specific gene expression activities by using ChIP-Atlas. The system will be one of the valuable resources of transcription regulation data available to all the researchers.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Shinya Oki, Tazro Ohta, Go Shioi, Hideki Hatanaka, Osamu Ogasawara, Yoshihiro Okuda, Hideya Kawaji, Ryo Nakaki, Jun Sese, and Chikara Meno. ChIP-Atlas: a data-mining suite powered by full integration of public ChIP-seq data. EMBO Reports &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.15252/embr.201846255&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.15252/embr.201846255 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
          <link>
          http://localhost:4000/en/2018/11/09/post2.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/11/09/post2.html</guid>
        </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>