<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dbcls news - Articles</title>
    <description>Database Center for Life Science (DBCLS) forms a base for integrating databases in life science field. Positioning itself as a specialized institution to provide biological databases and related services, DBCLS integrates and maintains biological databases mainly within Japan, conducts R&amp;D of information technology and develops new services to enhance usability.</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Renewed the DBCLS website</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that the DBCLS website was renewed today on June 5, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/06/05/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/06/05/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A paper “Promotion of malignant phenotype after disruption of the three-dimensional structure of cultured spheroids from colorectal cancer” was published in Oncotarget.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper “Promotion of malignant phenotype after disruption of the three-dimensional structure of cultured spheroids from colorectal cancer” was published in Oncotarget.
Dr. Hidemasa Bono and Dr. Hiromasa Ono from DBCLS have contributed to this work in comparative analysis of publicly available colon cancer dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open-access full paper can be found online at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.24641&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.24641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jose M. Piulats, Jumpei Kondo, Hiroko Endo, Hiromasa Ono, Takeshi Hagihara, Hiroaki Okuyama, Yasuko Nishizawa, Yasuhiko Tomita, Masayuki Ohue, Kouki Okita, Hidejiro Oyama, Hidemasa Bono, Takashi Masuko and Masahiro Inoue
“Promotion of malignant phenotype after disruption of the three-dimensional structure of cultured spheroids from colorectal cancer”
Oncotarget. 2018; 9:15968-15983.
DOI: 10.18632/oncotarget.24641&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/26/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/26/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A paper “Construction of a simple evaluation system for the intestinal absorption of an orally administered medicine using Bombyx mori larvae” was published in Drug Discoveries &amp; Therapeutics.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper “Construction of a simple evaluation system for the intestinal absorption of an orally administered medicine using Bombyx mori larvae” was published in Drug Discoveries &amp;amp; Therapeutics.
Dr. Hidemasa Bono and Dr. Takeru Nakazato from DBCLS have deeply contributed to this work in comparative analysis of human and silkworm(Bombyx mori) gut transcriptomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open-access full paper can be found online at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5582/ddt.2018.01004&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5582/ddt.2018.01004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ichino F, Bono H, Nakazato T, Toyoda A, Fujiyama A, Iwabuchi K, Sato R, Tabunoki H
“Construction of a simple evaluation system for the intestinal absorption of an orally administered medicine using Bombyx mori larvae”
Drug Discov Ther. 2018; 12(1):7-15.
DOI: 10.5582/ddt.2018.01004&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was also supported by NIG-JOINT (2014-A171 &amp;amp; 2015-A155) and computations were partially performed on the NIG supercomputer at the ROIS National Institute of Genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/22/post2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/22/post2.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A research paper of the analysis of environmental DNA retrieved from petal surfaces of flowering cherry was published in Journal of Plant Research.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A research paper “Collaborative environmental DNA sampling from petal surfaces of flowering cherry Cerasus × yedoensis ‘Somei-yoshino’ across the Japanese archipelago” was published in Journal of Plant Research. Tazro Ohta and Shuichi Kawashima from DBCLS contributed to this work and are listed as authors.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The online article is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10265-018-1017-x&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10265-018-1017-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The SharedIt URL by Springer Nature to provide the read-only full text access is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdcu.be/HmdX&quot;&gt;http://rdcu.be/HmdX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was produced by the NGS Field 4th meeting, the conference of high-throughput sequencing technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nig.ac.jp/nig/2018/03/research-highlights/20180312.html&quot;&gt;The commentary&lt;/a&gt; is available on the website of National Institute of Genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/22/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/22/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A paper “YummyData: providing high-quality open life science data” was published in Database.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper “YummyData: providing high-quality open life science data” was published in Database.
Dr. Yasunori Yamamoto and Dr. Atsuko Yamaguchi in DBCLS and Dr. Andrea Splendiani in Novartis Institutes for Biomedical Research contributed to this work.
The open-access full paper can be found online at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/database/article/doi/10.1093/database/bay022/4925801&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/database/bay022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Database, Volume 2018, 1 January 2018, bay022
doi: 10.1093/database/bay022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More RDF databases are freely available on the Internet through SPARQL endpoints in life sciences. In this situation, researchers have difficulty in finding designated ones which have needed data with higher reliability. They proposed and introduced a knowledge sharing place where database providers and users can communicate with each other, so that life science databases can be more usable than ever.
This work was firstly discussed in the Biohackathon and has been continued through international collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/14/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/03/14/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>DBCLS server maintenance, 9-12 Mar 2018</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the system maintenance, our servicess will be temporarily unavailable. We are sorry for the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintenance schedule: 9 Mar 2018 17:00 〜 12 Mar 2018 9:00 (GMT+9)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/26/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/26/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A paper “Differentiated Embryo Chondrocyte plays a crucial role in DNA damage response via transcriptional regulation under hypoxic conditions” was published in PLOS ONE.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A paper “Differentiated Embryo Chondrocyte plays a crucial role in DNA damage response via transcriptional regulation under hypoxic conditions” was published in PLOS One.
Dr. Hidemasa Bono in DBCLS deeply contributed to this work in collecting hypoxia related genes from public gene expression database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open-access full paper can be found online at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192136&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0192136&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hideaki Nakamura, Hidemasa Bono, Keiko Hiyama, Takeshi Kawamoto, Yukio Kato, Takeshi Nakanishi, Masahiko Nishiyama, Eiso Hiyama, Nobuyuki Hirohashi, Eisaburo Sueoka, Lorenz Poellinger, Keiji Tanimoto
“Differentiated Embryo Chondrocyte plays a crucial role in DNA damage response via transcriptional regulation under hypoxic conditions”
PLOS ONE 2018; 13(2): e0192136.
doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0192136&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/22/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/22/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>An interview with four authors of the FANTOM5 collection entitled “Increasing usability of FANTOM5 data” was published in the Research Data at Springer Nature website.</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;An interview article “Increasing usability of FANTOM 5 data” in the Research Data at Springer Nature website was published.
This article describes the background of how to publish &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/sdata2017105&quot;&gt;a paper of RefEx&lt;/a&gt; which enables users to easily search and view gene expression data, the explanation of the FANTOM 5 project　that is also included in RefEx and the Scientific Data journal. Also, in this article, the importance of reusing public data is mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/08/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2018/02/08/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>NBDC/DBCLS Training: AJACS Hamamatsu, 16-17 Jan. 2017</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;AJACS is a training workshop by the National Bioscience Database Center (NBDC) and DBCLS.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2017/12/14/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2017/12/14/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Exhibition of servicess and databases and organizing workshops and forums on ConBio2017</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We introduced our servicess and databases on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.aeplan.co.jp/conbio2017/&quot;&gt;ConBio2017&lt;/a&gt;(Kobe, Japan). We also provided a “data analysis help desk” at our institute’s booth on #ConBio2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/en/2017/12/11/post1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/en/2017/12/11/post1.html</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>